A Finding Aid to the Roger Crossgrove Papers, 1888-2012, bulk 1950-2006, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1950s-1999; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 7-8, OV 24
  - Oversized Redevelopment Projects from Box 8, Folder 6, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 24)
- Exhibition Files, 1950-2005; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 3 Linear feet Boxes 8-11
  Extensive exhibition files cover numerous exhibitions of Crossgrove's artwork, including Roger Crossgrove Selected Works: Photographs 1978-1993 (1993), Three Decades (1961-1990): Works on Paper and Photographs (1991), Monotypes Today (1976-1977), Monotypes Today II (1978), Monotypes Today III (1979), Monotypes Today IV (1980), Impressions Gallery and Slater Museum monotype exhibitions, and a traveling monotypes exhibition. Other files include faculty and alumni exhibitions, exhibitions in Mexico, and Original Art from Contemporary Children's Books (1987-1988). Files typically contain a wide variety of materials, such as correspondence, catalogs and announcements, information about individual works of art, and notes.
  - General, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - General, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10-14)
  - General, 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
  - General, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - General, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Roger Crossgrove Selected Works: Photographs 1978-1993 (1993), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Roger Crossgrove, Three Decades (1961-1990): Works on Paper and Photographs (1991), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Roger Crossgrove Solo Exhibitions, San Miguel and Mexico City, 1950-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - 20th Anniversary Alumni Exhibition (1996), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Aetna Institute Gallery Exhibitions, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Arte Grafico Norteamericano 1967, Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Atrium Gallery Exhibition (1982), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Berkshire Art Association Exhibitions, 1971-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Bethel Gallery Contemporary Prints (1977), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Beth El Temple Exhibition and Sale, 1969-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Boston Museum Exhibition (1991), Photographs, Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Canton Gallery on the Green Exhibitions, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Children's Literature Presentation Schedule, circa 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut Watercolor Society Exhibitions, 1970-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
  - De Cordova Museum Drawing Competitions, 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Essex Art Association, Annual Shows, 1973-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Lists of Artists and Artwork, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Exhibits, University of Connecticut Art Department, 1969-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17-19)
  - John Stevenson Gallery, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Jose Gutierrez Exhibition, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - List of Connecticut Exhibitions, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - List of Exhibitions 1960, Fleisher Memorial, 1952-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Master Eagle Gallery Exhibitions, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Material for Articles on Mexico Exhibitions for Artists Proof, 1964-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Meeting Notes and Proposals for Exhibitions, 1983-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Mexico Exhibitions, General, 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Mexico Exhibitions, Articles and Correspondence, 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Mexico Exhibitions, Jorge Hernandez Campos, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Mexico, Exchange Exhibitions in Graphic Art, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - IBM Gallery, Mexican Graphics Exhibition (1968), 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Smithsonian Institution, Mexican Graphic Art (1967-1968), 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Mexican Print Show and Article, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Monotypes, Articles, 1972-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Monotypes, Bibliography, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Monotypes, Exhibitions, 1954-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12-15)
  - Monotypes Today (1976-1977), Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Monotypes Today II (1978), 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Monotypes Today II (1978), Entry List, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Monotypes Today III (1979), 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
  - Monotypes Today III, Folio, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Monotypes Today IV (1980), Correspondence, Biographies, Photographs, 1976-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Impressions Gallery Monotype Exhibition (1977), Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Slater Museum Monotype Exhibition (1976-1977), Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Traveling Monotypes Exhibition (1977), 1976-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Montclair Art Museum Exhibition, Far and Near (1969), 1968-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Munson Gallery Exhibition and Sales, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Museum of Modern Art, Recent Drawings-U.S.A. (1954), Entries, circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Mystic Art Association Exhibitions, 1971-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 29-30)
  - Mystic Art Association Exhibitions, 1971-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Original Art from Contemporary Children's Books (1987-1988), Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Nathan Oliveira Exhibitions, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New Haven Paint and Clay Club, 1973-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern Connecticut Art Association, 1976-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Pace Wildenstein MacGill Gallery, Frederick Sommer Exhibition (2005), Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Papermania Exhibition (1999), Dealers, Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Ridgefield, Connecticut Exhibitions, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sharon Creative Art Foundation, 1971-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Slater Memorial Museum Exhibitions, Fall 1977, 1977-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Slater Memorial Museum-Norwich Exhibitions, 1971-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ward Eggleston Galleries, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Personal Business Records, 1963-2009; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 11, OV 24 (Box 11)
  Business records include seven personal budget ledgers, records of artwork sales and purchases, and expense documentation for art supplies and professional memberships.
  - Paintings on Loan, circa 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Personal Budget Ledgers, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Personal Budget Ledgers, circa 1957-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Professional Expenses, 1969-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Purchase of Artwork, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Sale of Artwork, 1963-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Oversized Budget Ledgers from Box 11, Folders 13-14, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 24)
- Printed Material, 1906-2012; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 8.5 Linear feet Boxes 11-20, 23. OV 24
  This series consists of event invitations, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, flyers, gallery and museum publications, newspapers, periodicals, and posters. The Art of Childhood auction preview book contain annotations by Crossgrove.
  - About Crossgrove, 1966-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Arts Organizations, 1958-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20-23)
  - Business Cards, circa 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1948-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25-27)
  - Clippings, 1948-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-17)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1950-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18-21)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1950-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1-16)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1950-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-17)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1950-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1906-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13-17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1906-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1-16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1906-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-12)
  - Events, General, 1951-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
  - Event, The Art of Childhood, Auction Preview Book, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Flyers, 1967-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Galleries, 1966-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17-18)
  - Letterhead, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Museum Publications, 1939-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - Newsletters, 1963-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4-7)
  - Periodicals, 1937-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8-18)
  - Postage Stamps, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Posters, circa 1980-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2-4)
  - Sales Catalogs, Artwork and Art Books, 1968-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5-9)
  - University Publications, 1962-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10-13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 14-17)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous from Box 19, Folders 14-17, 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
  - Oversized Posters from Box 19, Folders 2-4, circa 1980-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 24)
- Artwork, 1933-2000; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 20, 23
  Included in this series are drawings, illustrations, monotype prints, and sketches for a Unitarian church bulletin by Crossgrove; artwork by Crossgrove's children, Louis Owens, Warner Pfeiffer, and Vincent and Bette Perez; and various collages, doodles, and sketches.
  - Drawings and Illustrations by Crossgrove, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Monotype Prints of Three Figures by Crossgrove, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Botanical Thought Card Print, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - By Family, circa 1950s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Collages, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Crossroads, Series of Collages, circa 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Doodles, 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Drawing by Cory Crossgrove, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Drawings by Ethan and Elinor Parker, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Drawing by Warner Pfeiffer, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Geometric Colored Papers, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Painting by Louis Owens, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Paintings of Animals, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Pen Drawing, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Photography by Steve Balkin and Others, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Print of Luna by Carl Crossgrove, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Sketches, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Sketches for Unitarian Church Bulletin Cover Designs, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Vincent and Bette Perez Baby Announcement, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Oversized Monotype Prints by Crossgrove from Box 20, Folder 4, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
  - Oversized Artwork by Family from Box 20, Folder 6, 1950s-1980s; 1968 - 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
  - Oversized Photographs by Others from Box 20, Folder 17, 1968 - 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
- Sketchbooks, 1950s-1980s; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 20, 22-23
  Eighteen sketchbooks contain mainly figure drawings, still life drawings, and occasional notes written by Crossgrove and others.
  - Sketchbook 1, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Sketchbook 2, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Sketchbook 3, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Sketchbook 4, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Sketchbook 5, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Sketchbook 6, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Sketchbook 7, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Sketchbook 8, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Sketchbook 9, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in Boxes 22-23.
  - Oversized Sketchbooks 10-15 from Box 20, circa 1950s-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
  - Oversized Sketchbooks 16-18 from Box 20, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
- Photographic Material, 1920s-2006; Series 12; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 21
  Photographic materials includes photographs and negatives taken by and of Crossgrove, his artwork, and the artwork of others including Doreen Elizabeth, Helene Rechovsky, and Alfredo Zalce. Also included are travel photographs.
  - By Crossgrove, 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Of Crossgrove, circa 1960s-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Family and Friends, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Crossgrove with Artwork, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Crossgrove's Artwork, circa 1950s-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Crossgrove's Early Artwork at University of Nebraska and University of Illinois, 1949-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Artwork, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Artwork by Doreen Elizabeth and Helene Rechovsky with Photograph of Unidentified Woman, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Of Alfredo Zalce, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Parking Lot, Dumpster, and Middletown Plaza, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Travel, People and Scenery, 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Negatives of Artwork, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Negatives and Photographs of Monotypes, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Slide of Artwork, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Stereogram of Bonaventure Cemetery in Savannah, Georgia, circa 1889; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 15)